Hello everyone, welcome to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod，我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today with Erika we have a very aggressive lesson for you today.
今天我和Erika为大家准备了一节非常激烈的课程。
That's true, we've got a revolutionary lesson.
没错，我们带来了一节革命性的课程。
Yes, today at EnglishPod we're protesting.
是的，今天在EnglishPod我们要抗议。
So Erika, why don't you tell us what a protest is?
那么Erika，不如你来解释一下什么是抗议？
Well, when you protest something, you go into the streets and show your disagreement.
嗯，当你抗议某事时，你会走上街头表达你的不满。
Right, and you yell and you have signs and everyone's just protesting.
对，你会大喊大叫，举着标语，每个人都在抗议。
And the news comes and if it's not clear now, it'll be clear after the dialogue, I'm sure.
新闻也会来报道，如果现在还不清楚，听完对话后就会明白了，我敢肯定。
Definitely, definitely.
当然，当然。
So why don't we start with our vocabulary preview?
那我们开始词汇预览吧？
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
We have two words in our vocabulary preview today.
今天的词汇预览中有两个词。
The first is bankrupt.
第一个是破产。
Bankrupt.
破产。
So if a company goes bankrupt, what happens?
那么如果一家公司破产了，会发生什么？
It means the company doesn't have any more money.
意思是这家公司没有钱了。
So it can't pay salaries.
所以它无法支付工资。
It can't pay anything.
它什么也付不起。
Can't pay its bills, yeah.
无法支付账单，是的。
So basically if it's bankrupt, it's probably going to close.
所以基本上如果破产了，它很可能会倒闭。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, our second word today is bailout.
好的，今天的第二个词是救助。
Bailout.
救助。
B-A-I-L, bailout.
B-A-I-L，救助。
So bailout is when the government gives money to a company that is about to go bankrupt.
救助是指政府给濒临破产的公司提供资金。
That's true, it's emergency money that will help save the company.
没错，这是帮助拯救公司的紧急资金。
Well these two words are taken directly from our dialogue.
这两个词直接来自我们的对话。
And in today's dialogue, we're going to bring you live to a newscast.
在今天的对话中，我们将现场连线到新闻播报。
Right, so why don't we just listen to the dialogue?
好的，那我们直接听对话吧？
This is Action 5 News reporter Sarah O'Connell reporting live from Washington, D.C. where
这里是Action 5新闻记者Sarah O'Connell从华盛顿特区发回的现场报道，那里爆发了一场抗议活动。
a protest has broken out.
数千名愤怒的市民正在抗议针对汽车制造业的救助计划。
Thousands of angry citizens are protesting against the proposed bailout of the auto manufacturing
先生，先生，我是Action 5新闻的Sarah O'Connell，能告诉我们发生了什么吗？
industry.
是的，是的，我们在这里是因为我们觉得这不公平。
Sir, sir, Sarah O'Connell, 10 on 5 News, can you tell us what's happening?
先生，先生，我是Action 5新闻的Sarah O'Connell，能告诉我们发生了什么吗？
Yeah, yeah, we're here because we feel this is an injustice.
是的，是的，我们在这里是因为我们觉得这不公平。
The financial irresponsibility of big business has to stop.
大企业的财务不负责任行为必须停止。
We're here to show the government that we don't like the way they're spending our tax
我们来这里是为了向政府表明，我们不喜欢他们花我们税款的方式。
dollars.
税款。
Sir, but what exactly is making everyone so angry?
先生，但到底是什么让每个人都这么生气？
It's an absolute outrage, Sarah.
这简直是令人发指，莎拉。
The U.S. government wants to give $25 billion of taxpayers' money to the auto industry.
美国政府打算用250亿美元的纳税人钱救助汽车行业。
These are companies that have been mismanaged and are now nearly bankrupt.
这些公司管理不善，现在几乎破产了。
I see.
我明白了。
But many supporters of the bailout argue that it could help save the jobs of millions of
但许多救助计划的支持者认为，这有助于保住数百万辛勤工作的美国人的饭碗。
hardworking Americans.
辛勤工作的美国人。
That may be true, and I for one don't want to see anyone lose their job.
这也许是真的，我也不希望看到任何人失业。
But how can these CEOs ask for a bailout when they're making millions of dollars?
但这些CEO们自己赚着数百万美元，怎么还有脸要求救助？
And then they have the nerve to fly to Washington in private jets.
而且他们还好意思乘坐私人飞机去华盛顿。
This costs hundreds of thousands of dollars.
这要花费数十万美元。
They're asking for money.
他们是在要钱。
That is just not right.
这太不像话了。
Good point.
说得好。
This is Sarah O'Connell reporting live from Washington, D.C.
我是莎拉·奥康奈尔，从华盛顿特区现场报道。
Back to you, Tom.
交回给演播室，汤姆。
Wow, these people are really angry.
哇，这些人真的很生气。
I think they're furious.
我觉得他们愤怒至极。
Well, I think they have some good points, and we'll talk about that later.
嗯，我认为他们说得有些道理，我们稍后再讨论。
But now it's time for Language Takeaway.
但现在到了语言学习时间。
Language Takeaway.
语言学习时间。
Yeah, there was some great language in this dialogue.
是的，这段对话中有很多很棒的语言表达。
A lot of language we use to express our anger.
很多用来表达愤怒的词汇。
Right.
没错。
And one of those words, and the first one for Language Takeaway is injustice.
其中一个词，也是语言学习的第一个词，是“不公正”。
Injustice.
不公正。
An injustice.
一种不公正。
So, an injustice is something that isn't fair.
所以，不公正就是指不公平的事情。
It's totally unfair.
完全不公平。
It's unfair, yeah.
不公平，是的。
This is an injustice.
这就是一种不公正。
Let's look at our second word, outrage.
我们来看第二个词，“愤怒”。
Outrage.
愤怒。
An outrage.
一种愤怒。
So, Erica, why don't you give us an example on how you would use outrage.
那么，艾丽卡，你给我们举个例子，说明如何使用“愤怒”这个词。
There's no more coffee.
没有咖啡了。
This is an outrage.
这太令人气愤了。
Yeah, there we go.
好了，就这样。
That's an outrage.
这太令人气愤了。
Okay.
好的。
Let's go to our next word now.
现在我们来看下一个词。
Breakout.
爆发。
So, we have some great examples on how we use breakout, so let's listen.
我们有一些关于如何使用“breakout”的好例子，我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
War is broken out in Antarctica as countries of the world fight for control of the icy
战争在南极洲爆发，世界各国为争夺这片冰雪大陆的控制权而战。
continent.
大陆。
Example two.
例子二。
Officials are warning that fighting could break out in the border regions.
官员们警告说，边境地区可能爆发战斗。
Example three.
例子三。
A forest fire broke out last night.
昨晚发生了一场森林火灾。
Well, this is a wonderful phrasal verb that means...
嗯，这是一个很棒的短语动词，意思是……
To begin suddenly.
突然开始。
Okay, so I think that's pretty clear.
好的，我想这很清楚。
Yeah.
是的。
Breakout.
爆发。
Let's go to our next word now.
现在我们来看下一个词。
Mismanaged.
管理不善。
So, when something is mismanaged, it's...
所以，当某件事被管理不善时，就是……
Not managed properly.
没有妥善管理。
Managed poorly.
管理得很差。
Poorly, right.
很差，对吧。
Yeah.
是的。
So, our final word today is...
那么，我们今天的最后一个词是……
Have the nerve to.
有胆量做。
I think this one also is a little bit difficult to understand.
我觉得这个词也有点难理解。
Yeah, but we have some great examples prepared for you, so let's listen to them.
是的，但我们为你准备了一些很好的例子，我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
I've been in love with you since the third grade, but I didn't have the nerves to tell
我从三年级就爱上你了，但我一直没勇气告诉你
you.
你。
Example two.
例子二。
I don't believe it.
我不信。
You have the nerve to ask me for money when you know I've just lost my job.
你明知道我刚刚失业，居然还有脸向我要钱。
Example three.
例子三。
What?
什么？
You have the nerve to bring your new girlfriend to visit my mother.
你居然有脸带你的新女友来拜访我母亲。
So have the nerve to is like dare to do something, right?
所以“have the nerve to”就是“胆敢做某事”的意思，对吧？
Yeah, how dare you.
对，就是“你怎么敢”的意思。
Yeah.
是的。
Have the nerve to.
竟敢。
It's like, I can't believe you would do that.
就好像，我简直不敢相信你会那么做。
Yeah, I think that's quite clear.
是的，我觉得那很清楚。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
A lot of great words in our dialogue today.
今天的对话中有很多好词。
And also, we have some really interesting grammar in today's dialogue.
而且，今天的对话中还有一些非常有趣的语法。
Right.
对。
So, today, let's look at some grammar breakdown.
那么，今天我们来分析一下语法。
Grammar breakdown.
语法解析。
In this section, grammar breakdown, we show you a particular grammar structure and explain
在本节语法解析中，我们会展示一个特定的语法结构，并解释
a little bit about how that structure affects meaning.
该结构如何影响含义。
So, it's not really about getting the grammar perfectly right, it's about understanding
所以，重点不在于把语法弄得完全正确，而在于理解
the meaning.
其含义。
Right.
没错。
And in today's lesson, we saw some really great examples on how we use the present perfect
在今天的课程中，我们看到了一些很好的例子，说明我们如何使用现在完成
tense.
时。
Let's listen to an example from the dialogue.
让我们听一个对话中的例子。
Where a protest has broken out.
一场抗议已经爆发了。
See the verb here, break out, like a protest has broken out, happened in the past, right?
看这里的动词，break out，比如一场抗议已经爆发了，发生在过去，对吧？
Right.
对。
And it's still going on now.
而且现在还在继续。
Exactly.
没错。
So, present perfect is used when we're talking about an event that happened in the past and
所以，当我们谈论一个发生在过去并且
is continuing on now.
现在仍在继续的事件时，就会用现在完成时。
Exactly.
没错。
Or is continuing to affect now.
或者现在仍在产生影响。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, I think that's pretty clear.
好的，我想这已经很清楚了。
Yeah, but now, if you want to indicate or if you want to demonstrate that the action
是的，但现在，如果你想表明或展示这个动作
has finished, the event is over, then you would say it like this.
已经结束，事件已经过去，那么你会这样说。
A protest broke out.
一场抗议爆发了。
In this form, you see that the protest is over.
在这种形式中，你看抗议已经结束了。
It happened yesterday already.
它昨天就已经发生了。
Right.
对。
And I think it's really emphasizing the fact that it is no longer affecting the present
而且我认为它是在强调它不再影响当前
moment.
时刻。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So, remember, the difference between present perfect and simple past.
所以，记住，现在完成时和一般过去时的区别。
Now, if you want to know more about these tenses, present perfect and simple past, be
现在，如果你想了解更多关于这些时态——现在完成时和一般过去时——的信息，
sure to go to our website at EnglishPod.com.
一定要访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
In the grammar section, you can find some more great examples and a really clear explanation
在语法部分，你可以找到更多精彩的例子以及关于这些时态如何构成的
on how these tenses are formed.
非常清晰的解释。
But now, we are ready to listen to our dialogue a second time.
但现在，我们准备再听一遍对话。
This is Action 5 news reporter Sarah O'Connell reporting live from Washington, D.C., where
这里是 Action 5 新闻记者 Sarah O'Connell 从华盛顿特区发回的现场报道，
a protest has broken out.
一场抗议活动已经爆发。
Thousands of angry citizens are protesting against the proposed bailout of the auto manufacturing
数千名愤怒的市民正在抗议针对汽车制造业的拟议救助计划。
industry.
行业。
Sir, sir, Sarah O'Connell, Channel 5 News.
先生，先生，我是第五频道新闻的莎拉·奥康奈尔。
Can you tell us what's happening?
您能告诉我们发生了什么吗？
Yeah, yeah.
好的，好的。
We're here because we feel this is an injustice.
我们在这里是因为我们觉得这不公平。
The financial irresponsibility of big business has to stop.
大企业的财务不负责任必须停止。
We're here to show the government that we don't like the way they're spending our tax
我们来这里是为了向政府表明，我们不喜欢他们花我们税款的方式。
dollars.
税款。
Sir, but what exactly is making everyone so angry?
先生，但到底是什么让大家这么生气？
It's an absolute outrage, Sarah.
这简直是令人发指，莎拉。
The U.S. government wants to give $25 billion of taxpayers' money to the auto industry.
美国政府想用纳税人的250亿美元救助汽车行业。
These are companies that have been mismanaged and are now nearly bankrupt.
这些公司管理不善，现在几乎破产了。
I see.
我明白了。
But many supporters of the bailout argue that it could help save the jobs of millions of
但许多救助计划的支持者认为，这可以帮助挽救数百万
hardworking Americans.
辛勤工作的美国人的就业机会。
That may be true, and I for one don't want to see anyone lose their job.
这也许是真的，我个人也不希望看到任何人失业。
But how can these CEOs ask for a bailout when they're making millions of dollars?
但这些CEO们自己赚着数百万美元，怎么还有脸要求救助？
And then they have the nerve to fly to Washington in private jets.
而且他们还好意思坐私人飞机去华盛顿。
This costs hundreds of thousands of dollars.
这要花费数十万美元。
They're asking for money.
他们是在要钱。
That is just not right.
这太不像话了。
Good point.
说得好。
This is Sarah O'Connell reporting live from Washington, D.C.
我是莎拉·奥康奈尔，从华盛顿特区为您现场报道。
Back to you, Tom.
交回给你，汤姆。
Okay, Erica, so what do you think about this situation?
好的，艾丽卡，你对这种情况怎么看？
About the bailout of the auto industry?
关于汽车行业的救助？
Yes.
是的。
I think it's a bad idea.
我觉得这是个坏主意。
Why?
为什么？
There's so many reasons.
原因太多了。
I mean, I don't think it's fair for us as taxpayers.
我的意思是，我认为这对我们纳税人来说不公平。
Well, I guess I'm not really an American taxpayer, but I don't think it's fair for the taxpayers
嗯，我想我并不是美国纳税人，但我认为让纳税人
to have to pay for the mismanagement of these companies.
为这些公司的管理不善买单是不公平的。
I mean, they've got so much debt.
我的意思是，他们负债累累。
They've produced cars that nobody really wants to buy, and now they're in trouble.
他们生产的车没人想买，现在他们陷入困境了。
And it's not our money that should be spent on saving them.
而且不应该用我们的钱来拯救他们。
Yeah, I would agree with you on that.
是的，我同意你的看法。
But you do have to take into consideration the fact that if these companies go bankrupt,
但你必须考虑到，如果这些公司破产，
millions of people will lose their jobs, and not only the people that work at the factories,
数百万人会失业，不仅是工厂的员工，
but also people that work for other companies that supply these factories.
还有为这些工厂供货的其他公司的员工。
Yeah, I mean, I see what you're saying, Marco, but at the same time, we can't support an
是的，我明白你的意思，马可，但与此同时，我们不能支持一个
industry that isn't working properly.
运转不正常的行业。
I mean, if one of these companies goes bankrupt, it's going to be terrible, but it will force
我的意思是，如果其中一家公司破产，那会很糟糕，但这会迫使
the other two companies, perhaps, to manage themselves better, to streamline and become
另外两家公司或许更好地管理自己，精简流程，变得
more efficient.
更高效。
I just think it will be better in the future.
我只是觉得从长远来看会更好。
Well, it could be, but also maybe all three companies can go bankrupt.
嗯，有可能，但也许三家公司都会破产。
It would be sad because the American car, the American auto industry is a symbol of
那会很可惜，因为美国汽车，美国汽车工业是繁荣的
prosperity.
象征。
It's also the symbol of the American culture in general.
它也是美国文化的象征。
I guess that's true.
我想确实如此。
So it would be a shame for it to go bankrupt because everyone owns a car in the United
所以如果它破产了会很遗憾，因为在美国，每个人都有车，
States, or most people, and it's just something that we can't lose.
或者说大多数人都有车，这是我们不能失去的东西。
But it is an interesting topic and we also want to know your opinions about this.
但这是个有趣的话题，我们也想知道你们的看法。
Yeah, listeners, please come to our website at EnglishPod.com and tell us what you think
是的，听众们，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，告诉我们你们对
about this bailout and about this lesson.
这次救助以及这节课的看法。
On the website, we'll post a link to the news article where you can read a little bit more
在网站上，我们会贴出新闻文章的链接，你们可以了解更多
about this because this is actually going on now.
相关内容，因为这件事正在发生。
That's true.
没错。
Well, everyone, thanks for listening and until next time, goodbye.
好了，各位，感谢收听，下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
再见。